i think it should be a rule that when
the sun sets
you put your b-dubs head on before you
go to bed
whoa
this is a really strange angle anyway
let's start today's episode every now
and again on the hermitcraft server i
come back to a spot from the beginning
of the season
and i just think about it all the time
because to this day
i still don't know
how the arrow of mystery has stayed
there no one is allowed to touch this
bamboo and i'm hoping that this
mysterious arrow
will remain
for the world download so everyone else
can think about this every day but
enough of the arrow of mystery there's
something i want to do over in the base
and that is whoa
how have you got here where's your
friends now there's never just one is
there there's always like a group of
them
i think i saw something are they in here
pillagers have infiltrated my mansion
and i can't find them oh no there's
another one i've never seen a pillager
scout party
it's so spread out that's very strange
but anyway what i wanted to work on
today is the mob farm that i mentioned
last episode now under here there is a
huge amount of space that constantly
spawns mobs so i thought what i'd do is
turn it into a more productive space i
don't even really need the mob drops
i'll be honest sometimes i need some
bones sometimes i need some string but
on the whole i don't actually need it
but i want it i want this place to feel
much more productive in general so what
we're going to do is we're going to kick
off today's episode with a mob farm
creation now this is a green special
because it's going to be
my own design and it's probably gonna be
really laggy and
probably very inefficient so let's go
[Music]
right so here we go the mob farm look at
that look at it rain oh my goodness it
actually works so it's not inefficient
it's just a little bit laggy with
redstone so here
i'm enjoying this a lot it's been
running for a little while now and this
is what i mean by being the most
inefficient farm ever i'm just using
old-school redstone wiring
but this these are the bits
that are the the laggy bit so eventually
when the power comes back to this line
it will go full circle it then powers
all of them
and there's several layers of these so
there's a lot of resources on the line
here
and if we check down here
it has been pretty good i've got to say
now i mean the only things you really
need from a mob farm are gun powder
bones and string there's no not much use
for rotten flesh there's not much use
for arrows these days because you got
infinity bow but on the whole a very
successful farm
for the start of an episode
i mean we're only a few minutes in and
we're already winning i didn't mean to
get up in your grill like that i just
ran into a wall but before we continue
the rest of the episode i've got to say
a couple of words and that's about the
storylines on the server you see we're
having an awful lot of fun with the
mycelium resistance and the whole turf
war and i personally am having a really
good time but what's not nice and not
fun is the amount of nasty comments that
are appearing in people's videos and
comments section it really upsets me to
see
my viewers or viewers of hermitcraft in
general spreading some really nasty
things or attacking other hermits simply
because they're getting involved in a
really fun storyline it's not fair and
it's not really it's not really on scar
in particular is one of my best friends
on the hermitcraft server and we've been
having such a nice time
having a little bit of a fight on the
hermitcraft server there's absolutely no
ill feelings we do talk to each other
all the time what i would really love to
see is seeing positive comments
supporting both sides of this turf war i
want to see people supporting the
resistance but i also want to see people
particularly my fans supporting scar and
hep and everything else there is no
right and wrong on this side it's just a
silly silly war on hermitcraft it's kind
of what we do so i'll leave it at that
but please do bear in mind there are
real people behind the screen
and all we want to see is our fans being
nice to everyone involved each other
and the hermits but speaking of let's go
to the shopping district where we've got
some more things to do so i've been
wondering what on earth i'm going to do
next because we've actually got a few
reviews by far the best treasure hunt
i've ever done by green this week okay
well that's the only treasure hunt you
did don't know who that one was what an
adventure 10 out of 10 i would pay the
double
i'm guessing the double means that was
corrales and green's build box hunt made
me the happiest man on earth b-dubs
well i mean that's pretty good reviews
so
what do you think 200 diamonds for a new
treasure hunt something maybe treasure
quest is what's up next and there may
only be three because these take a long
time to make so as for an update on the
mycelium resistance check it out i think
all of the sheep have been destroyed oh
no no no there is one agent still going
keep keep fighting my dude keep munching
the turf
the frames the frames hurt here so as
you can see
it's done pretty well not perfect but
pretty well so yeah there's still
there's still some hip hip hep dogs hip
dogs on the loose and mycelium buyback
two stacks for five diamonds and a
couple of dogs on the scene diamonds two
for two stacks of mycelium whoa
no diamonds take from the throne
so sorry hold on so
if we put in a stack of mycelium
fight you get two stacks of mycelium
five diamonds this has taken me four
times to read this
hep thanks you for your service
boo i i
scar you've made a mistake scar this is
this is
you have handed us the shopping district
these these diamonds will be ours
dude
we can just farm a load of mycelium this
was such a mistake i'm losing my mind in
fact this might be the time
to take
i need to press the emergency button we
need to call a meeting of the mycelium
resistance because we have over 34
shulker boxes shulker boxes
of mycelium already so we know roughly
that there's seven and a half stacks of
diamonds in there due to mumbo's video
so if we do some maths very quick i need
money my calculator
okay
this this was just like a maths paper
examination from school i can't believe
that those exam papers have finally
actually applied to me in real life it's
taken years of being out of school but
it was like okay so if you have nine
diamonds per diamond block and there's
64 blocks in a stack and they're seven
and a half stacks how many mycelium do
you need to farm in order to take the
diamond throne it sounds like a
legitimate maths question on an exam
paper i can't believe it okay so if my
math is correct we need approximately 64
shulker boxes full of mycelium i mean
that's a lot of mycelium don't get me
wrong in fact we should just call the
group in fact who's online pretty much
all of the resistance is online or most
of them so we're gonna call them right
now
oh man
i've been wanting to use this giant red
emergency meeting button for so long
okay here we go we're gonna use it
[Music]
oh my goodness
yes
wait i think some people got stuck
emergency meeting
i think it didn't work quite as
perfectly i think
okay it worked for most of us
looks like a couple people got stuck uh
hello can i just say etho that's the
most amazing thing i've ever seen an
actual emergency meeting button that
just takes us here
hopefully
for a few people at least yes
i have no idea what happened with you
um and it put me like halfway out of the
wall so i had to like break through the
ceiling to get in i hope you hope you
guys weren't too busy um but there's
like been a quite a big development i
don't know if any of you've been to town
hall recently but the emergency meeting
is very much an emergency because scars
decided very foolishly
to
buy mycelium
for i think two stacks of mycelium for
five diamonds and he says you can take
diamonds from the throne
wow
dudes we've already that's a good deal
that is a really good deal that's insane
like we are gonna we're gonna we're
gonna take all his diamonds basically is
what i'm saying if we if we work
together to get the remaining mycelium
needed we can take the diamond throne oh
we got this easy
how much do we need okay so it was like
a legitimate exam paper question working
it out but according to my maths it is
64 shulker boxes of mycelium
wow it's a lot it's still a lot because
the diamond throat
is yeah it is a lot but we already have
34 shulker boxes so we're already over
halfway
so i'm thinking if we all go to the
mushroom island the other one
we farm up a bunch of shulker boxes
we can legitimately
by the law that scar has laid down we
can take his diamonds
that sounds good i mean he sounds like
he's done derp although i need to clear
my inventory first if that's okay i've
been building stuff yeah i was rudely
interrupted korean cheese but that's
what the meat emergency meeting's for
that is true actually yeah and it worked
to charm good job etho well that little
warning would have been nice though well
done what were you doing
i wasn't out
i think i
oh was
did we stop you getting a box or did you
get the box no i wasn't i wasn't in the
game
okay right sure so let's get our shovels
together
a bunch of shulker boxes and let's farm
here we are the mushroom island that
we're about to decimate is everyone
you're not even
i'm in f5 mode dude okay
all right everyone get your game face on
we're about to go and decimate this
island are you ready oh
xp you look adorable
[Laughter]
oh rent your etho
yeah jeff and that's disturbing wait
what yeah it's it's it's pretty
disturbing
how do i look ether put my game face on
we are dashingly
awesome we all look extremely handsome
are you ready to make this island let's
do it
you really are b-dubs etho
uh we have similar traits here
gentlemen as the scientist of this group
i'd like to point out a very serious
irony go on
we have destroyed a natural mushroom
island to regenerate another
mooshroom island
[Laughter]
very true
but yeah isn't it it's the hep's job to
protect the environment we're just here
to send a message
yeah that is true
it's about the principle well as as the
scientists of the group i don't approve
but good job everybody that's 64 shulker
boxes of my cdm collected we have done
it and i've i think we've gotta we gotta
we gotta do a big shout out to impulse
who isn't here but he already like
collected half of the title so
impulse he's a he's the real hero here
we need to take this over to the buyback
scheme before uh scar figures out that
the enormous mistake he's made so i
think i think the numbers have done i've
asked etho as well to run the numbers do
they check out yeah so i kind of gave up
on that okay right well okay
i'm trying to figure it out this is kind
of good it is complicated i i'm pretty
sure it's right so right let's take all
these over because we're about to buy us
a diamond throne i've uh i've calculated
it all oh wait where have they gone if
we all picked some up there was 65 boxes
of mycelium here all full all verified
run the numbers should be okay so now we
using this buyback program we take down
the diamond throne and replace it with
mycelium which isn't actually oddly it's
not the first time this has happened so
yeah yeah definitely also we should
probably get this done quick scar isn't
online so
yeah it's true he could he could turn up
at any point
oh
we're not leaving until we get every
diamond off this throne although to be
fair even if he did catch us like we're
not doing anything wrong we're just you
know following his thing all right wait
we've definitely overpaid then because
there's way less diamonds than was that
you know this mayor is mismanaging funds
because there's i mean it is outrageous
there is so many less there's like a
stack and a half less diamonds than
there should be so i it doesn't actually
matter if our math is wrong because
we've definitely paid enough
yeah this is what we're talking about
it's about the principle it's about the
principle i mean
yes
our maths was wrong because he's been
mismanaging funds okay right now we take
the diamonds we take them to the base
and we put them in the vault simple i do
want to point that out the scar is
online so we should we'll bodyguard
we'll bodyguard don't worry all right
let's get out of here uh so i've i've
got to break it to you guys this is like
a false false ball vault because there's
uh i was wondering if there was a button
or something
there's just a sign that says vault
[Laughter]
[Music]
so for now i think i think we just until
we can make something prop proper we
just uh we leave the diamonds in this
chest okay that's great they'll come
through here and they'll be like where's
the vault i can't rob this thing
okay right the diamonds will be safe
there for now they don't know where the
base is i will call this
an enormous success team good job we've
taken the diamond throne from our mayor
and
i guess the plan now
what do i don't know what we do with it
let's just see what scar does job well
done guys all right don't forget to put
your ender pearl back in the emergency
meeting thing and then yeah i'll see you
at the next emergency
so
we have completely covered or replaced
the diamond throne with mycelium i'm not
sure if they've seen this yet but i'm
sure a fair amount of people will have
seen it
it is actually kind of it's kind of
beautiful in its own resistancy kind of
way so i have an idea of what to do with
the diamonds but i actually genuinely
need to wait and see what scar is going
to do with this mycelium
i kind of hope that he
takes this down
because that would help me with my plan
to no end so we'll see hopefully he'll
take the mycelium and hide it away
somewhere
now i did say last episode that i would
go ahead
and use mumbo's spookificator the
self-portrait
so that's what we're gonna do i've not
used this before but
we'll see what we come out with
so it costs 16 diamonds
16 diamonds to change my skin
sleep before the spookification it will
only hurt a lot
also put items in the chest okay well
this doesn't sound good this sounds like
i'm definitely gonna die right 16
diamonds going in
stand on the iron here we go
is this it this isn't very spooky
what are these
oh great rockets
am i yeah okay straight up kills me
nice mumbo nice
right let's respawn and
it doesn't look like my skin's even
changed
yep
that's cursed it's not your traditional
spooky
it's been up spooky
uh yeah
that's certainly nightmare fuel isn't it
and to make it even worse i could take
off oh good oh
that's not your traditional spooky but
i'll give you it worth 16 diamonds
well
this is a
i wouldn't call it spooky but it's
certainly scary so i was flying around
the shopping district and there are
still some sheep left over
but every now and again i come across
one of the hep or hip wolves now i can't
find one right now but i read a comment
here's one here's one that's been
decimating everything look he's he's
going he's going for it look he's gonna
see that sheep and he's
you protect him cow no look here he goes
this is why we're losing sheep you see
not doing a very good job
he's doing the side shuffle
okay there we go
it took you a while there buddy right
his eyes went red that was scary so i
heard that llamas actually go for wolves
now i didn't know this ev i've been
playing minecraft for oh i forgot about
my face
i've been playing minecraft now for 10
years and i didn't know that llamas i
know llamas aren't as 10 years old but
i didn't know they went for wolves and i
never thought i would say this but i
need to use the llama shop llama drama
i want to check if there's any merit to
these
to these comments because if that's the
case we need a llama army to take care
of the walls that were taking care of
the sheep and their their one diamond
block each
dang that's uh that's expensive do i
just click this what happens no does
llama drama even work what about this i
think it might be empty of llamas oh
right okay select your favorite llama
white llama gray llama brown llama
creamy llama let's go for a brown llama
and then we press this button and then
we should get
a llama maybe they're all out i'm having
a hard time getting hold of a llama oh
oh there it is there he is
okay we got ourselves a fresh llama
that was surprisingly difficult i think
i think they're running low on llamas so
i never thought i'd i can't believe i've
actually had to buy a llama
i never saw this coming this is this has
been here
since the start of the season pretty
much really early on
and i just thought
why would you sell llamas
when i actually asked myself when am i
ever going to need a llama here we are
here we are
war does weird things to you right so
i've got myself a lead
and we're going to see if there's any
merit to these comments saying that
llamas are the answer
he doesn't want to leave llama drama he
definitely he really doesn't want to
leave come on
he's really reluctant what the heck
no
come on he doesn't want to leave brian
no come on
enough
no enough of this
i've
come on
now i've i've actually walked alpacas in
real life i know they're not the same as
llamas but this is surprisingly accurate
come on
he's so stubborn
do i need a carrot in my hand or
something do you like carrots
having to drag him against his will
oh no no no no no no no no no he's run
like the wind
i didn't i didn't expect this issue at
all i almost don't even i don't even
want to force this on you look i'll put
you back here if you just help me out
he's just breaking the lead
okay there we go he seems to have given
up now
why why why did he why are you so
reluctant
i've never seen that before right we're
taking this guy to see if he'll uh
attack the wolves
right where's that pesky hep wolf there
he is whoa
it looks like he is scared of the llama
let's take him off the lead and see what
yeah he's going for him do you see that
he just spat at him let's see if we can
lead this wolf to the llama and he's
yeah he's booking it
right
you come with me let's see what happens
yeah it goes for him
oh and it hurts him
i think this is an unfair fight if he's
on the lead you get him
go on i never thought i'd see a fight
between a llama and a wolf like this
oh and then the wolf attacks the llama
dude i think the llamas will lose this
fight
i can't believe what i'm what i'm
witnessing oh llamas are the answer
look how majestic they are oh my
goodness he's looking at me like why did
you bring me into this why
why are you dragging me into this war
well there we have it we learn something
new every day llamas will go and spit at
wolves and apparently their spit
kills them which is really weird it's
odd because i think the hep bass
actually looks like a llama quite a lot
i mean look at that it is identical so
anyway i think that is all we have time
for in today's episode we actually got a
lot done we have replaced the diamond
throne with mycelium we have made a
successful mob farm and we have proven
that the emergency meeting button does
indeed work and it's amazing so thank
you very much for watching i hope you
enjoyed today's video and i shall see
you in the next one good bye